Truth is the first casualty of war
Redacted is a war, drama film directed by Brian De Palma.
A fictional documentary discusses the effects the Iraq war has had on soldiers and local people
through interviews with members of an American military unit, the media, and local Iraqis.
Angel Salazar, played by Izzy Diaz.
Lawyer McCoy, played by Rob Devaney.
Master Sergeant Sweet, played by Ty Jones.
Soldier, played by Anas Wellman.
Sergeant Jim Vasquez, played by Mike Figueroa.
Soldier, played by Yanal Kassay.
Redacted is a 2007 American war film written and directed by Brian De Palma.
It is a dramatization, based on real events the 2006
Mahmudiyah killings in Mahmoudiyah, Iraq, when U.S.
Army soldiers raped an Iraqi girl and murdered her along with her family.
This film, which is a companion piece to an earlier film by De
Palma, Casualties of War (1989), was shot in Jordan.
Redacted premiered at the 2007 Venice Film Festival, where
it earned a Silver Lion Best Director award.
It was also shown at the Toronto International Film Festival, the New York Film
Festival and the Buenos Aires International Festival of Independent Cinema.
The film opened in Spain, and in fifteen theaters in limited
release in the United States on November 16, 2007.
The film received mixed reactions from critics and a poor
financial response in its limited U.S.
The film explores themes of journalist, tank, iraq, murder, soldier.
The tone is emotional.